<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="113"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[The CA$H RESIDENCE

                       for FAMILIES: 3  Edition
                                                     rd














































                                  David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                        Critical Praise for The CA$H


                                      Residence

                   “In  The  CA$H  Residence, author  David  Saucer
                   crystallizes the complex and makes it incredibly
                   simple. He  dishes out an understanding of PES
                   (Personalized Economic System) like a gourmet
                   chef serves a fine meal; only Saucer gives you the
                   whole  satisfying  taste  in  what  seems  like  one
                   savory bite…Saucer makes the American Dream
                   seem  doable and  achievable even  on  a  limited
                   household income. He removes the confusion and
                   the sense of overwhelming and replaces it with
                   financial     hope.      Consistency,      long-term
                   commitment, and a  simple strategy equate to a
                   debt  free  and  prosperous life  with  you  in  the
                   driver’s  seat…As  one  who  has  purchased
                   countless books that cost me money but never
                   provided a return on my investment, I delight in
                   discovering this goldmine in print that opens an
                   immediate pathway to lifetime financial freedom.”

                          Dr. Fred Childs, Executive Coach, Mentor,
                          Author, Entrepreneur, and Minister

                   “In my opinion, the book you currently hold in
                   your hand is one of the most concise and relevant
                   in the market today… David Saucer has over two
                   decades of  experience  in  the  financial  services
                   industry.  His  ability  to  communicate  intricate





                                               3]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               financial ideas in a simple manner will make this
               book a very valuable resource.”
                       B. Chase Chandler, Best-Selling Author
                       of  The  Wealthy  Physician  and  The  Wealthy
                       Family

               “I have read David’s book cover to cover, and I
               believe that it will help anyone who is looking to
               be more efficient with their dollars.  Creating long
               term wealth is not about a particular investment
               vehicle, but about process.  David does a great job
               of explaining the process of  how we should all
               think  about  our  money, and  also  explains  the
               instrument that can  be  used  to  warehouse the
               dollars until a great opportunity presents itself.”
                       Jay  Gentry  (Financial  Services  Industry
                       Veteran)

               "It was not until I watched a family member's
               401k take serious losses during 2008 that I began
               to consider retirement options. I'm not a big fan
               of losing money that I worked hard for. Neither
               am I fond of worrying over uncontrollable risks,
               fees, and uncertain future tax rates. After some
               personal research and a conversation with David,
               I realized there was another way to gain my
               projected goal for retirement as well as have
               access to my money if I needed it punishment
               free."
                       Reverend Michael Nutter]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   “David  has  taken  the  complex  and  made  it
                   accessible! This book is carefully crafted and filled
                   with meaningful examples. A user-friendly read.”

                          Dr. Robert Hogan, Assistant Professor of
                          Accounting

                   "The CA$H Residence is more than a book about
                   how to best invest your money; there are lots of
                   books that do that.  But this is a book that will
                   change the  way you  think  about investing.   It
                   challenges the conventional wisdom using simple,
                   straight-forward  language,  not  complicated

                   financial  jargon.    It  makes its  case  plain  using
                   Biblical principles and real-world analogies. This
                   book made me completely change the way I plan
                   my  retirement.    Thank  you,  David,  for  your
                   insights!"

                          Chuck Drvol, Valued Client

























                                               5]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                            The Cash Residence for Families
                                         rd
                                        3  Edition
                          Copyright © 2022 by (David Saucer)

                   All rights reserved. No part of this book may be
                   reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any
                   means  without  written  permission  from  the
                   author.

                   Disclaimer: This book is meant to provide general
                   information on financial subjects and strategies.  It
                   should not be used as sole guidance for making
                   financial decisions. Mr. Saucer recommends that
                   you seek a qualified and experienced professional
                   when  implementing  a  financial  strategy  or
                   purchasing any investment or insurance product.
                   The  author  assumes  no  responsibility  for  any
                   errors or omissions.

                   The contents of this book are the opinions of Mr.
                   David Saucer  at  the time  of  this  writing.   For
                   educational use only.

                                      Printed in USA

















                                               7]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence






                     To my girl, Cindy, and our children, Kaleb and Chloé
                     Thank you for following me when I chose a less-traveled path.

                          Two roads diverged in a wood, and I —
                              I took the one less traveled by,
                           and that has made all the difference.
                                      ~ Robert Frost














































                                               9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                          TABLE OF CONTENTS


                   DEDICATION……………………...…….9

                   FORWARD…………………………....….15
                   B. Chase Chandler

                   INTRODUCTION: Savings vs. Investing....17

                   Savings is money you cannot afford to lose.

                   CHAPTER 1: Objective Decisions and the
                   Right Vehicle…………...…………………..21
                   Why do so many people go astray?

                   CHAPTER 2: Following the Herd…………27

                   Learning from the Parable of the Ham

                   CHAPTER 3: The Search for the Perfect
                   Asset……………………………………......33
                   Hint: It’s not a shoebox or mattress.

                   CHAPTER 4: The Usual Suspects...…..…….39
                   Taking stock of securities and other popular assets.


                   CHAPTER 5: Financial Assets and Taxation..45
                   Tax the seed or the harvest?







                                               11]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               CHAPTER 6: The Phenomenon of Compound
               Interest…………...………………………….53
               The “eighth wonder of the world.”


               CHAPTER 7: Inside the CA$H Residence......57
               Become your own banker.

               CHAPTER 8: What Do the Experts Know?...65
               Behind the scenes with people who know.

               CHAPTER 9: The Private Reserve Account...75
               Guide your own financial destiny.


               CHAPTER 10: Flexing Your Way to a Brighter
               Future……………………………………….81

               CHAPTER 11: The CA$H Residence and
               Families…………………...................................87
               The PES solution for the people who depend on you.


               CHAPTER 12: Case Studies..……........……..91
               The PES solution in action.

               CHAPTER 13: Starting the Conversation.......95
               Some will, some won’t; so what?

               Appendix A: Types of Life
               Insurance…………………………………....99]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Appendix B: A Personal Plan for Financial
                   Success……………………………………...101

                   Appendix C: Suggested

                   Reading………………………….…………..105

                   Citations……………….……………...……..107


                   ABOUT THE AUTHOR…………………...109







































                                               13]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                       Forward by B. Chase Chandler


                   In my opinion, the book you currently hold in your
                   hand is one of the most concise and relevant in the
                   market today. Giving this reading your full  and
                   undivided attention could be the most impactful
                   financial  decision  you  make  this  year.  David
                   Saucer has over two decades of experience in the
                   financial  services  industry.  His  ability  to
                   communicate intricate financial ideas in a simple
                   manner  will  make  this  book  a  very  valuable
                   resource.

                   The  strategies and  principles  David  delineates,
                   while  somewhat unknown to  the  majority,  are
                   those  that  have  helped  some  of  the  most
                   successful people in our country’s success build
                   their businesses. As you read, I think you’ll find
                   that the unconventional thoughts shared will begin
                   to  excite  you  as  you  see  the  vision  of  what’s
                   possible.

                   Unfortunately, there are many who will disregard
                   or refuse to study what Mr. Saucer is giving. Many
                   financial  ‘gurus’,  family  members,  friends,  and
                   colleagues  will  not  understand how  important
                   these issues are. As you will soon appreciate, it is
                   vital  to  keep  an  objective point  of  view  while
                   internalizing this material.






                                               15]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               I can tell you one thing for sure—these ideas have
               changed my life. Yes, there are some who still do
               not understand, some individuals that I  am (or
               was) very close to. Even so, the truth will set you
               free. Let the truth set you free.

               B. Chase Chandler
               Best-Selling Author of The Wealthy Physician and
               The Wealthy Family]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence





                                    Introduction:
                              Savings vs. Investing


                   The book you have in your hand will provide you
                   with  an  understanding  of  a  powerful  savings
                   strategy. Not an investment strategy, but a savings
                   plan.  The  information  enclosed  is  not  about
                   becoming  extraordinarily  wealthy—it’s  about
                   being extraordinarily wise.

                   Think of this book as the start of a conversation.
                   After  reading  this  simple  but  profound  bit  of
                   information, you will have the opportunity to see
                   how this savings strategy could fit in your overall
                   financial picture.

                   In Dwayne Burnell’s A  Path to Financial Peace of
                   Mind, the author differentiates between savings and
                   investing—terms that, over  the years,  have  been
                   used  to  describe  a  wide  variety  of  financial
                   products.  We  sometimes make  the  mistake  of
                   using the terms interchangeably, as though they
                   mean the same thing. But saving and investing are
                   two very distinct concepts. Your savings consist of
                   money that you  cannot afford to  lose. Money you
                   invest is money that is subject to the risk of loss.

                   Any money that you designate as savings should
                   be in a financial vehicle with low risk, easy access,
                   and no fear of loss of principal. Money in savings


                                               17]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               builds gradually and safely. To be clear: when you
               have money in the stock market, either directly or
               through  an  investment  fund,  the  principle  is
               subject to loss.

               A  solid  financial  strategy includes  two  distinct
               groups of money. There should be money that is
               saved and not subject to risk  of loss, and there
               should  be  money  that  is  invested.  A  proper
               financial strategy will have these two components
               clearly  distinguished.  Invested  money  has  the
               potential for greater growth, but also has a greater
               risk of loss.

               Over  the  years,  we’ve  met  with  thousands of
               individuals from all walks of life. Individuals in the
               beginning stages of their accumulation of assets
               and individuals who are now at the stage where the
               assets  or  being  used  for  distribution.  We  are
               convinced that this savings strategy should be a
               piece in every person’s financial puzzle.

               However, this savings strategy may have a special
               significance for families. Intrigued? Read on!


               David A. Saucer
               2022

               Mobile: 225-907-6000
               https://www.safemoneydavidsaucer.com/]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Set an appointment with David today:
                   https://calendly.com/davidsaucer




















































                                               19]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence

















                    Chapter One: Objective Decisions
                              and the Right Vehicle



                   People are pretty much the same, wherever you
                   go. We share the same dreams and aspirations. We
                   want to  take  care  of  our  families.  We  want  a
                   chance to build something that lasts. And when we
                   reach retirement age, we’d like to reward ourselves
                   for a life of hard work and planning. And when we
                   reach the end of life’s journey, we want to leave
                   something behind for those we love.

                   Simple dreams, really. The tragedy is, most people
                   fail to reach these shared aspirations. According to
                   Forbes magazine, the average American faces “the
                   greatest    retirement      crisis   in     American
                   history…too frail to work and too poor to retire.”
                   As of 2010, more than 75 percent of retirement-
                   age  Americans  had  less  than  $30,000  in  their
                   retirement  accounts.  Corporate  pensions  have




                                               21]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               been eliminated in many cases, and both public
               and private pensions are in jeopardy.

               Ask yourself, if so many people share the same
               dreams, and share the same dismal results, exactly
               what are they doing wrong? Would it surprise you
               to know that most people make the same mistakes
               with money?

               The financial market offers a ton of investment
               opportunities  to  consider.  I  have  friends  and
               clients  whose  chosen  career  paths  involved
               working a  job  with  the state  government or  a
               municipality. They all long for the day retirement
               comes. They worked specifically for the future and
               for the pension they would receive. But families
               have more at stake than a quiet job and a quieter
               retirement.

               I’ve always looked for the most efficient way to
               lead my family to personal financial freedom and
               designing a predictable retirement (should we ever
               choose to retire).

               My  search  has  taken  me  all  over  the  country;
               attending  workshops,  seminars,  and  reading
               hundreds of books. Long hours of study refined
               my  understanding  of  the  subject  of  financial
               freedom. In the pages that follow, I’m going to
               give you a condensed version of what I learned.
               Consider this a “conversation starter,” for one of
               the most important discussions of your life.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   What I discovered is  a little unorthodox, which
                   won’t  surprise  you  all  that much  (especially  if
                   you’ve been following my argument closely).  The
                   best solution to the problem of wealth building is
                   not  the  most  popular  solution.  If  the  popular
                   solutions worked best, more people would reach
                   their financial goals, and less would be facing a life
                   of toil and poverty.

                   What we’re talking about is the proper financial
                   vehicle—a term  that refers  to a  place  to  hold
                   money  and/or  produce  a  return.  A  savings
                   account is  a  financial  vehicle.  So  are  shares  of
                   stock. The  metaphor of  a  vehicle  is  appropriate
                   because  we  want  our  investments  to  “go
                   somewhere” (like a comfortable retirement)!

                   The vehicle metaphor is even more useful when
                   you make a direct comparison between choosing a
                   car and financial choices. When you make a car
                   purchase, what are the things you consider before
                   buying? Not everyone considers the same things.
                   For example, a young couple with an infant might
                   rank safety pretty high on the list.  A successful
                   businessman may  want a  prestigious car.  What
                   options do you find important in a car?

                       •  Safety

                       •  Speed
                       •  Handling



                                               23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



                   •  A Track Record of Performance
                   •  Low Operating Cost

                   •  Efficiency

               Likewise, we choose our financial vehicles with a
               list of options—in many cases, the same criteria as
               for your car!

                   •  Safety - You don’t want to lose your money
                       overnight!
                   •  Speed  -  How  fast  will  your  investment
                       grow?
                   •  Handling -  You want control and use  of
                       your funds.
                   •  A Track Record of Performance -  Not a
                       recent gimmick.
                   •  Low  Operating  Cost  –  You  want  your
                       financial vehicle to make money for  you,
                       not your financial advisor.

                   •  Efficiency –  You want advantageous tax
                       treatment.

               Of course, some people make both their car and
               their investment choices for subjective reasons,
               including feelings and emotions. A car looks cool,
               so it must be safe, right? The neighbors bought the
               same model as  the man down the street. That
               means the car has low operating costs, right?]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                              Everything in life is somewhere else; and
                              you get there in a car.
                                          E.B. White

                   I’m going to suggest that we use objective reasons
                   instead—reasons which are  based on  historical
                   data and hard facts. Over the course of this book,
                   I will compare common financial vehicles and the
                   features,  options and  benefits included in  each
                   one. That way, you can make an educated decision
                   based on objective reasoning.

                   As you read, keep important investment criteria in
                   mind. Do you want a fast, safe financial vehicle
                   with  a  proven  track  record  for  success  and
                   durability?  Or  do  you  want  to  follow  your
                   neighbor’s lead  and  hope  he  knows  what he’s
                   doing?



























                                               25]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                    Chapter Two: Following the Herd

                   Why  do  so  many  people  make  the  wrong
                   investment  and  retirement  decisions?  If  the
                   majority of Americans reach retirement age unable
                   to stop working, with nothing to pass on to their
                   children but debt, why do so many people follow
                   in their footsteps?

                   There’s  a  simple  answer  to  that  question.
                   Objective decision-making takes some work. You
                   have to do a little reading. You have to seek out
                   expert opinions. By contrast, it’s easy to follow the
                   herd.

                   Herd  behavior is  an  interesting phenomenon.
                   Suppose you’re hungry, and you find yourself in
                   front of two restaurants. Both look good. Which
                   one should get your business? You could hook up
                   a laptop or visit the library computer, do a search
                   for reviews, and see what people think of the two
                   restaurants.

                   But like I said, you’re hungry. Really hungry!



                                               27]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Herding behaviors occur frequently in  everyday
               decisions, based on observation or discussion with
               others. Suppose that earlier, when both restaurants
               were  empty,  the first  customer  of  the  evening
               chose the restaurant on the left at random. Later,
               a couple looks in both windows. The restaurant on
               the  right  is  empty.  They  move  back  to  the
               restaurant  on  the  left.  And  so  on,  with  other
               customers making an assumption of quality based
               on  the  size  of  the  crowd.  “They  must  know
               something,” you think as you join the herd. This
               sort  of  collective  behavior  is  called  an
               information cascade—joining in the behavior of
               others  through  observation,  despite  personal
               preferences or knowledge.


                          Once the herd starts moving in one
                       direction, it’s hard to turn it, even slightly.
                                    Dan Rather


               Not that a decision like where to have dinner or
               what sports team to root for will affect the rest of
               your  life.  But  what about  choosing a  financial
               vehicle? Do you really want to make a financial
               decision based on herd behavior? Birds and insects
               flock and swarm. Smart individuals decide things
               objectively!

               Some herd decisions are born from habit. Sales
               guru  Zig  Ziglar  tells  a  story  that  pertains  to]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   decision-making. He observed his wife cutting off
                   the end of a ham before placing it into the oven to
                   bake.  He  asked  why  she  made  the  cut.  She
                   explained that she’d always baked a ham that way,
                   and that her mother had always done the same.
                   Did he not like the ham?

                   Sure, he told her. He was simply curious. But the
                   curiosity  didn’t go  away, and when he met  his
                   mother-in-law later  in  the  week,  he  asked  her
                   about the ham. Her answer was much the same as
                   his wife’s: “My mother always cut off the end of
                   the  ham  before  baking.”  His  wife’s  mother’s
                   mother was a great cook. If something worked for
                   her, then it had to be the right thing to do.

                                                               Curiosity
                                                                unsated,
                                                                      he
                                                                resolved
                                                              to ask the
                                                                  family
                                                              matriarch.
                                                              Yes,  the
                                                                      old
                                                                 woman
                                                              admitted;
                   the end of the ham had to come off before baking.
                   It seems that when she’d first married, she and her
                   husband didn’t  have  much  money  for  kitchen
                   equipment. The one baking pan they owned was




                                               29]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               small, and most hams wouldn’t fit. So she’d cut off
               the end to make it fit.

               The chances are  good that your  parents had a
               passbook savings account. Does that mean you’re
               going to let passbook savings be the focus of your
               investment strategy? If you do, you may be cutting
               off more than just the end of your ham!

                             I stayed on my own path and
                             did not follow the herd. I
                             made a way for myself.
                               ~Eartha Kitt


               What about public opinion? If there’s a consensus,
               doesn’t      that    fact    indicate     something?
               Conventional wisdom is the body of ideas that’s
               accepted as truth by the public. Conventional means
               generally  accepted.  Orthodox.  (Unoriginal.)
               Wisdom is  a  scholarly body of  knowledge. Now
               here’s  a  thought:  Conventional  thought  is
               generally  accepted  without  close  objective
               examination. And wisdom is  scholarly thought,
               examined closely and revised as new knowledge
               becomes available.

               Doesn’t  it  strike  you  that  conventional,
               unexamined  thought  can’t  also  be  considered
               wisdom? That means “conventional wisdom” is an
               oxymoron—an inherently contradictory term, like
               jumbo shrimp and heavy diet.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   The  fact  is,  the  progress  of  mankind can  be
                   marked by the mistaken notions of conventional
                   wisdom, from the belief in a “flat earth” to the
                   belief that the “stock market is safe.” Nuggets of
                   so-called  conventional  wisdom  are  not  only
                   unexamined, they are often dead wrong.

                       •  In 1899, Charles Duell,  an  official at the
                          U.S. Patent Office, noted, “Everything that
                          can be invented has been invented.” Two
                          years later, vacuum cleaners were invented.
                          The year after that, air-conditioning.
                       •  Lord Kelvin, President of the Royal Society,
                          echoed popular  sentiment when  he  said,
                          “X-rays will prove to be a hoax.”
                       •  Thomas Watson, President of the Board at
                          IBM, said, “I think there’s a world market
                          for maybe five computers.”

                   Worse, conventional wisdom is often an obstacle
                   to the acceptance of newly acquired information,
                   to  introducing  new  theories  and  explanations.
                   “Wisdom” acts as a barrier that must be overcome
                   by legitimate alternative views.

                   Will conventional wisdom stop you from realizing
                   your full  economic potential? What I’m arguing
                   for here is a conscious, objective approach to the
                   topics  of  investment  and  retirement  planning.
                   Strip  away herd behavior and its  close cousins,



                                               31]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               habit and consensus, and what’s left is fact-based
               decision making. And  that’s a  process you  can
               bank on.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                    Chapter Three: The Search for the
                                    Perfect Asset


                   As I said earlier, we will take an objective look at
                   the most common financial vehicles in which we
                   store our money. To list a few:

                       •  Shoebox
                       •  Stock Market
                       •  Certificate of Deposit (CD)

                       •  Money Market Account
                       •  401K / IRA
                       •  Real Estate
                       •  CA$H Residence/Private Economic
                          System (PES)

                   You might find it funny that we listed a “shoebox”
                   here. The other cliché you  might have heard is
                   “hiding your money in a mattress.” Some people
                   don’t trust any investments at all. They figure that
                   if  they hold tight to their cash, they won’t lose
                   anything. (Chances are, you know somebody right
                   now who thinks that way!)



                                               33]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Are  they right?  No.  Let  me  introduce  another
               term:  opportunity costs.  Suppose  you  have  a
               choice between working an extra shift at your job,
               and going to an amusement park. Going to the
               park will cost you $100. But that’s not your only
               cost if you choose the amusement park. You pay
               to go to the park, and you lose the extra wages you
               might have otherwise earned. Opportunity costs
               are the loss of a potential gain from other choices
               when  you  settle  on  one  alternative.  In  our
               example, if you settle on the amusement park, you
               pay to play, and you lose wages, too.

               Look at our list of financial vehicles. Which ones
               carry hidden opportunity costs? (Here’s a hint: if
               the investment isn’t liquid, you’re locked in. You
               can’t  take  advantage of  a  new,  more  lucrative
               opportunity.)

               But  first,  let’s  compare  some  of  the  positive
               features  of  each  type  of  investment  here.  I
               encourage you to objectively compare the benefits
               that each financial vehicle carries:

               Shoebox
                   •  Safety

                   •  Liquidity
                   •  Control

               Stock Market
                   •  Liquidity]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                       •  High Contributions

                   C.D. (Certificate of Deposit)
                       •  Safety

                       •  High contributions
                       •  Collateral opportunities
                       •  No- loss provision

                   Money Market Account
                       •  Safety
                       •  High contributions

                       •  Collateral opportunities
                       •  No- loss provision

                   Real Estate
                       •  Tax-deferred growth
                       •  High contributions

                   CA$H Residence (PES)
                       •  Tax-deferred growth

                       •  TAX-FREE           distribution     (Tax-Free
                          Retirement)
                       •  High contribution limits
                       •  Collateral opportunities
                       •  Safety—Principle that is NEVER at risk

                       •  Guaranteed loan options
                       •  Unstructured loan payments
                       •  Liquidity—use and control
                       •  Heirs receive inheritance TAX-FREE



                                               35]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer




               You might not be  familiar with the last  of the
               financial  vehicles.  The  Personal  Economic
               System (PES) is a financial vehicle with positive
               options  that  directly  address  some  of  the
               shortcomings of other financial vehicles.

               What exactly are those shortcomings? We already
               mentioned  opportunity  costs  inherent  in  the
               “shoebox” method of saving. The same holds true
               for  passbook savings. If  you  can safely  earn  a
               higher  rate  of  return  elsewhere,  you  lose  by
               selecting the lower rate. Opportunity costs are a
               concern.

               A second concern is complexity. Investing in some
               financial vehicles is relatively easy. Most banks, for
               example, offer similar certificates of deposit. But
               investing in the stock market isn’t nearly as simple.
               Stocks can be  risky.  Even the so-called experts
               who study the market for a living have a tough
               time predicting where the market is headed. And
               stocks aren’t the  only risky  venture. If  the real
               estate  market  takes  a  nosedive,  you  can  find
               yourself stuck with property that’s worth less than
               the mortgage!]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence















                   Liquidity  is  another  important  consideration.
                   Liquidity involves the availability of funds. Money
                   in a shoebox is very liquid—you grab a handful
                   and spend it! Other investments come under the
                   heading of  what I  call  a  money prison. Many
                   financial vehicles restrict your  use of  your  own
                   money! You can obtain funds from a certificate of
                   deposit, for example, but you may pay substantial
                   penalties for  withdrawing funds  outside  of  the
                   original terms of the agreement. Real Estate can
                   be a tremendous financial vehicle, but if our equity
                   or cash is needed, you may have to sell the asset to
                   use it. That can take weeks…or months.

                   For comparison’s sake, let’s look at an investment
                   that the experts have been praising for decades—
                   the 401 K plan. Conventional wisdom says that’s
                   the  safest  path  to  retirement.  One  thing’s  for
                   sure—if you bank on a 401k, you won’t be alone.
                   The rest of the herd will be there with you. But


                                               37]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               let’s take an objective look at the drawbacks to
               most 401k plans:

                   •  Many plans are booby-trapped (full of
                       hidden fees that can eat away your
                       growth).
                   •  Lack of control.

                   •  Limited investment options.
                   •  The specter of inflation haunts most long-
                       term plans.
                   •  Promotes false security (allowing bad
                       spending habits and an increased debt
                       tolerance).

                           To start off, I’ve never been a fan
                            of the 401k…it’s a real loser’s
                               bet if you think about it.
                                  Daniel Ameduri


               And you don’t know what the future will bring.
               That means you can put your money into an IRA
               for 30 years and still not know how your financial
               future will end up. Do you remember the stock
               market  crash  of  2008?  Can  you  imagine  how
               people felt as they reached retirement age, only to
               read about the crash in the morning paper? Can
               you imagine losing a lifetime of planning just when
               you count most on the money?]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                    Chapter Four: The Usual Suspects

                   The 401K isn’t the only gathering place for the
                   herd. Let’s take a few moments to look at popular
                   savings and investment vehicles and see what they
                   have to offer.

                   Conventional wisdom says you can count on the
                   stock market to fund your retirement. In one form
                   or another, 84 percent of Americans own stock at
                   one time in their lives. Think about that statistic.
                   That’s a lot of people buying into a rollercoaster.
                   Take a look at the chart that follows. Over a twelve
                   year period beginning in the year 2000, the ups and
                   downs added up to nothing. The Dow started at
                   12,000 and ended at 12,000. During the same time
                   period, 31 percent inflation robbed investors of
                   their buying power. The chart does indicate a clear
                   winner—brokers charging transaction fees!













                                               39]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer


























               The  truth  is,  there’s  a  kind  of  excitement
               associated with buying and selling stocks, similar
               to the excitement of dice or a roulette wheel. To
               be fair, gambling is a zero-sum game (winners are
               matched  to  losers)  that  doesn’t  depend  on
               production or profits. But casual investors have
               little or no chance to be successful. Experts weigh
               many  factors  before  investing  in  a  company,
               including:

                   •  Capitalization
                   •  Revenues

                   •  Profits
                   •  Competitors
                   •  Industry trends
                   •  Price  to  earnings  ratios  for  both  the
                       company and its competitors
                   •  Management]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                       •  Ownership
                       •  Balance sheet analysis

                       •  Stock price history
                       •  Stock options
                       •  Revenue and profit projections
                       •  Industry risks

                       •  Company risks

                   What happens if you beat the odds and your stock
                   jumps in price? When you sell the stock, you pay
                   capital gains tax. Or perhaps you hold onto the
                   stock,  praying  that you  can  ride  out  the  next
                   market crash.

                   Professional, full-time investment experts may be
                   willing to buy and sell stocks for you (for a fee),
                   but in the end, their expertise will never come with
                   a guarantee.

                   Mutual funds are a very popular financial vehicle.
                   If  you  rely  on  results  printed  in  the  fund
                   prospectus, though, you may be misled about what
                   kind of results to expect:

                       •  According to the Hulbert Financial Digest, 80
                          percent  of  mutual  funds  perform  below
                          their benchmarks.
                       •  Funds only advertise only “buy-and-hold”
                          results (ten years or more), despite the fact
                          that the average fund investor holds on to




                                               41]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



                       the  fund for  five  years  or  less.  For  that
                       reason,  most investors don’t capture the
                       results promoted in sales brochures.
                   •  The fund industry hopes investors won’t
                       mind a one percent fee rate. But according
                       to  the  Department  of  Labor,  a  fund
                       charging that fee rate over a 35-year period
                       will  devour  28  percent  of  your  savings
                       (assuming an annual return rate of seven
                       percent).
                   •  Comparing  the  results  between  mutual
                       companies  using  three  to  five  year
                       increments is ineffective. According to the
                       Hulbert  Financial  Digest,  a  15-year  track
                       record is necessary to eliminate blind luck
                       as  a  factor  in  performance  evaluation.
                       Given a  sufficient track record, the fund
                       industry’s  glaring  performance  holes  are
                       clearly visible.

               Another  common  financial  strategy  involves
               relying on  home equity  as  the centerpiece of  a
               retirement plan. Unfortunately, real estate offers
               another rollercoaster ride. The U.S. home market
               peaked in 2006, and the subsequent fall wiped out
               a  decade’s  worth  of  gains.  In  the  meantime,
               inflation eroded real value, leaving homeowners
               on the short end of the stick. And, as with stocks,
               the sale of a home results in capital gains taxes that
               eat any real profits.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Discouraging, isn’t it? Easy to see why the average
                   head of household in his or her sixties has only
                   saved a quarter of what’s needed for retirement!

                   Detailing the shortcomings of various investment
                   assets is easier than explaining why one particular
                   asset is superior to others. To understand why the
                   CA$H  Residence  Personal  Economic  System
                   (PES) has advantages over other strategies, you
                   need to fully understand two issues—taxation and
                   interest compounding. In the next two chapters,
                   we’ll briefly discuss those concepts. Then we’ll talk
                   more about the perfect asset!







































                                               43]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                   Chapter Five: Financial Assets and
                                       Taxation


                   One financial axiom advises, Taxes affect financial
                   decisions. Proponents of  the IRA note that 401k
                   plans defer taxes. Is that really a benefit? Let’s look
                   at  how  taxes  affect  investments, including  the
                   difference between tax deferred and tax exempt.

                   The tax man cometh is a phrase which puts fear in
                   the hearts of many. We all must pay taxes, and if
                   you achieve any financial success, your share of the
                   tax burden will be greater than others.

                   We always ask our clients, “What do you think?
                   Are taxes going up or down?” In my experience,
                   100  percent of  the people we  asked think that
                   taxes  are  going  up.  How  could  they  think
                   otherwise?  All  governments  overspend.  But
                   what’s disappointing is, taxes can go up with the
                   single stroke of a  pen and a  new law. Without
                   warning, lawmakers can change the rules and we
                   are required to play by them.





                                               45]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               With that kind of game, how can you win? Forget
               winning—how can you plan?

               Based on current law, we do have some options to
               minimize the tax burden if  we think ahead and
               implement  a  detailed  plan.  But  when  sorting
               possibilities, ask yourself, “Am I paying tax on the
               seed or the harvest?” Let me explain.

               The Gospels share over 40 parables. In many of
               them, Jesus uses an understanding of agriculture
               to deliver his message. Likewise, I would like to
               use an analogy using a farmer and his corn harvest
               to explain a problem with tax-deferred financial
               vehicles.

               In  the  beginning  of  the  season,  the  farmer
               prepares the ground, plants the seed and dreams
               of an abundant harvest. In some years, the harvest
               is  plentiful.  In  other  years,  the  farmer  is
               disappointed. When a  person decides  to put  a
               portion of their income into an IRA, they will get
               the tax deduction for the current year and pray for
               an abundant harvest at retirement.

               But after due diligence, you may find that an IRA
               may not be the best choice. If the farmer had the
               option to pay the tax on the seed or pay the tax on
               the harvest, which would he choose? I submit that
               in most cases, he would choose to pay the tax on
               the seed. By the time the harvest comes in, taxes
               may have gone up. In both the Roth IRA and in]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   the CA$H Residence system, we choose to pay the
                   taxes on the seed.

                   There are three tax strategies for your retirement:
                       •  Taxable
                       •  Tax-deferred

                       •  Tax-free

                   These three strategies will have an impact on your
                   taxes; either  today’s taxes or  tomorrow’s taxes!
                   Let’s  take a  closer  look  at  each of  these three
                   options:

                   Taxable - You pay tax now and invest with after-
                   tax dollars. Then, you pay tax on all the earnings
                   as they are earned. (Returning to our parable, this is
                   like  paying taxes on both the seed and on the
                   harvest as  it  grows!) These investments include
                   non-qualified accounts such as savings accounts,
                   CDs, stocks, and bonds.

                   Tax-deferred - You get a tax deduction now and
                   invest with pre-tax dollars. You won’t pay tax on
                   the earnings until you use them. (This is like paying
                   taxes  on  the  whole  harvest  later.)  These
                   investments include qualified accounts, such as a
                   Traditional IRA and most pension plans. There
                   are limits to how much you can contribute, and
                   you are required to take the money out after the
                   age  of  seventy and  pay  taxes.  (Remember our





                                               47]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               earlier question—will taxes be higher or lower in
               the future?)

               Tax-free -  You pay tax now (on the seed) and
               never pay taxes on the harvest. This is a ROTH
               IRA or the cash value in a life insurance policy.
               The ROTH IRA is limited to individuals under a
               certain  income,  whereas  the  life  insurance
               contributions can be much higher.

               But  which  path  is  best?  That  depends on  the
               future of taxes. Let’s look at some scenarios:


               What if Tax Rates Stay the Same?

               If tax rates stay the same, it doesn’t matter if you
               pay tax now (on the seed) or later (on the harvest).
               The final outcome is the same, believe it or not:


                 Tax Rate                Tax on     Tax on     Gain/
                 Remains                  Seed     Harvest     Loss
                 Constant   Investment   100,000    100,000
                 (35%)      After Tax     65,000
                            Future
                 7%         Value        251,570    387,030
                 Growth     Less Tax           0   <135,460>
                 for        Future
                 20 years   Investment   $251,570   $251,570      $0]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   What if Tax Rates Go Down?

                   If  tax rates  go down, you  would be  better off
                   paying tax on the harvest. In this scenario, you
                   would save $27,100 by investing in your IRA or
                   qualified accounts:

                    Tax Rate                 Tax on    Tax on     Gain/
                    Decrease                  Seed     Harvest     Loss
                    (35% to    Investment    100,000    100,000
                    28%)       After Tax      65,000
                               Future Value   251,570   387,030
                    7%         Less Tax           0   <108,360>
                    Growth
                    for        Future        $251,57
                    20 years   Investment         0    $278,670   $27,100

                   What if Tax Rates Go Up?

                   If tax rates go up, you would be better off paying
                   tax on the seed. By investing in your ROTH IRA
                   or your permanent life insurance policy, you could
                   have saved $27,100.


                    Tax Rate              Tax on     Tax on      Gain/
                    Increase               Seed     Harvest      Loss
                    (35% to   Investment   100,000   100,000
                    42 %)     After Tax    65,000
                              Future
                    7%        Value       251,570    387,030
                    Growth    Less Tax          0  <162,560>
                    for       Future
                    20 years   Investment   $251,570   $224,470   <$27,1000>




                                               49]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               So, what’s the best path? Since we can’t see the
               future, there’s no certainty. We don’t know where
               the tax rates will be in the future. We don’t know
               who will be elected, and what legislation they will
               enact.

               However, we do know that the government has
               hefty obligations. Social  Security,  Medicare and
               other programs must be funded. The country is, at
               the time of publication, $17 trillion in debt.  Our
               government is already struggling to fund programs
               in  today’s dollars  and our  obligations may well
               grow exponentially.

               The  government’s  main  source  of  income  is
               taxation, and additional funding could very well
               come from future tax increases.

               What is the best course of action? Planning! In
               order to properly prepare for retirement and your
               taxes, having a plan that maximizes the potential
               for you to reach your goals, while minimizing taxes
               is best.

               Important!  The  examples  in  this  chapter  are
               hypothetical, and should not be taken as specific
               tax or investment advice. There are no guarantees
               in any investment return or tax rate. But having
               your  assets placed  in  ways that minimize  your
               taxes now and in the future will be critical as the
               tax rates change.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   So I’ll ask you again: Do you think taxes will go up
                   or down?























































                                               51]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence














                     Chapter Six: The Phenomenon of

                               Compound Interest


                   Compound  interest  is  interest  added  to  the
                   principal  of  an  investment  so  that  the  added
                   interest also earns interest. The addition of interest
                   to  the  principal,  allowing  additional  interest
                   accrual, is called compounding.

                   Mathematically  speaking,  the  formula  below
                   expresses  compound interest.  P  is  the  original
                   principle and X is the rate of interest expressed as
                   a  decimal.  At  the  end  of  the  nth  year,  the
                   compounded amount will be:

                   P (1 + X) n


                                   Compound interest is the
                                eighth wonder of the world. He
                                who understands it, earns it ...
                                   he who doesn't ... pays it.
                                     ~Albert Einstein



                                               53]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Confused? Understand this:  the  growth of  the
               compound  amount—the  total  value  of  your
               investment—is exponential, not linear.  But that
               only  works  if  you  have  uninterrupted
               compounding.  To  understand  exponential
               growth, let’s  review  an  old  riddle:  Would  you
               rather I give you $1,000,000 dollars or a Penny a
               day doubled for 31 days? A million dollars would
               be great, but if I understand the phenomenon of
               uninterrupted  compounding  and  exponential
               growth, I would make a different choice.

                 Doubling a Penny for 30 Days
                 Day 1    $.01      Day 16  $327.68
                 Day 2    $.02      Day 17  $655.36
                 Day 3    $.04      Day 18 $1,310.72
                 Day 4    $.08      Day 19  $2,621.44
                 Day 5    $.16      Day 20  $5,242.88
                 Day 6    $.32      Day 21  $10,485.76
                 Day 7    $.64      Day 22  $20,971.52
                 Day 8    $1.28     Day 23  $41,943.04
                 Day 9    $2.56     Day 24  $83,886.08
                 Day 10  $5.12      Day 25  $167,772.16
                 Day 11  $10.24     Day 26  $335,544.32
                 Day 12  $20.48     Day 27  $671,088.64
                 Day 13  $40.96     Day 28  $1,342,177.28
                 Day 14  $81.92     Day 29  $2,684,354.56
                 Day 15  $163.84    Day 30  $5,368,709.12

               So which is it? $1,000,000 or $ 5,368,709

               Uninterrupted compound interest is an amazing
               phenomenon  that  works  best  when  given]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   additional time. For that reason, it’s particularly
                   important to start early. The CA$H Residence is
                   most  effective  for  young  savers,  allowing
                   exponential growth its full course.

                   Perhaps  you  recall  the  Biblical  parable  of  the
                   talents. A  wealthy man  entrusted a  number  of
                   talents (a monetary unit worth 20 years in wages)
                   to his servants. One servant received five talents,
                   another two,  and  a  third  servant received  one
                   talent. When the man returned from his journeys,
                   he asked each servant what they’d done with the
                   money he’d left  with them. The servant who’d
                   shepherded five  talents had invested them, and
                   doubled his talents—he now had ten. The servant
                   who had two talents had doubled his as well—he
                   now had four talents. The servant who had one
                   talent had taken it and buried it  in the ground,
                   untouched. He still had the one talent, intact—but
                   he’d done nothing to increase his wealth.


                                      Proverbs 13:11
                      Dishonest money dwindles away, but whoever gathers
                              money little by little makes it grow.



                   Then, the wealthy man did something unexpected.
                   He took the single talent and gave it to the servant
                   who already had ten, admonishing, “Thou wicked
                   and slothful servant!” The lesson is clear. Even the
                   Bible worries over opportunity costs! And though


                                               55]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               we all  start with different circumstances, and all
               end up with different results, it’s what we do with what
               we have that matters.

               Scripture is clear on the subject of wealth. Riches
               are a gift from God, to be used in His service. We
               are stewards, encouraged to increase the blessing
               through  investment  and  directed  toward
               generosity to others.

               Continuous  compounding is  a  wealth  creation
               strategy that allows you to be a wise steward of the
               gifts in your life. So, are you going to bury your
               money in the ground, or put it where it can do the
               most good?]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                     Chapter Seven: Inside the CA$H
                                      Residence


                   So  what  is  the  CA$H  Residence  Personal
                   Economic System (PES)? Simply put, this set of
                   oft-neglected financial  assets  comes  under  the
                   heading of cash value life insurance.

                   Cash value  life  insurance? It’s  been around for
                   centuries. Edmund Halley,  the astronomer who
                   discovered Halley’s  Comet,  also  developed the
                   first  actuarial table. His  work was continued by
                   James Dodson, the 18th century mathematician,
                   leading  to  the  first  life  insurance  company,
                   founded in London.

                   In the Americas, the first life insurance ventures
                   were     spearheaded  by         Presbyterian     and
                   Episcopalian churches.  When  the  massacre  of
                   George Armstrong Custer  at  the  Battle of  the
                   Little Bighorn stranded a number of families in the
                   West, public sentiment for the protection afforded
                   by  life  insurance  gave  birth  to  a  vibrant  new
                   industry.



                                               57]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Cash value life insurance—your CA$H Residence
               (PES) solution—is  a  financial  asset that  offers
               insurance protection, but also  accumulates cash
               value during the policyholder’s lifetime. This is a
               personalized economic system  with  a  stunning
               array of benefits, including:

                   •  Tax-Deferred growth
                   •  TAX-FREE           Distribution      (Tax-Free
                       Retirement)
                   •  Competitive returns

                   •  High Contribution limits
                   •  Collateral Opportunities
                   •  Principle that is NEVER at Risk
                   •  Interest that is Guaranteed
                   •  Guaranteed Loan options

                   •  Unstructured Loan payments
                   •  Liquidity, Use and Control
                   •  Safety
                   •  Heirs receive inheritance Tax- Free

               The CA$H Residence (PES) fits the criteria of the
               perfect savings asset. But you’ll  find that it’s so
               much more than that. When we refer to a personal
               economic system, we’re talking about aspects you
               may never  have considered. Let’s  take a  closer
               look at these possibilities.]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Generational Wealth

                   One aspect of the CA$H Residence strategy that
                   we’ve  not  yet  discussed  is  the  possibility  for
                   building generational wealth. We’re all familiar with
                   generational poverty, so difficult for the modern
                   family to escape. But instead of a vicious cycle of
                   poverty and meager entitlements, what if we were
                   empowered to not only better our circumstances,
                   but  start  a  pattern  of  wealth-building  that
                   continued on to our children and our children’s
                   children? That’s what using a tax-free distribution
                   is about!

                      When I was young I thought that money was the most
                     important thing in life; now that I am old I know that it
                                              is.
                                       ~Oscar Wilde



                   The gift that keeps on giving is a phrase that applies to
                   the CA$H Residence. Properly structuring a life
                   insurance  contract  through  a  series  of  gifted
                   premium payments allows you  to  provide your
                   family with substantial educational and financial
                   opportunities.  Because  the  savings  are  tax-
                   deferred  and  accumulate  within  the  account
                   policy,  the  cash  value  can  be  used  for  various
                   purposes, including college education, a business
                   opportunity or even a down payment on a home.
                   Furthermore,  the  cash  value  can  be  used  to



                                               59]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               supplement  retirement  income  later  in  the
               grandchild’s life. Would you like to permanently
               affect the financial trajectory of your family? The
               CA$H Residence may be the perfect asset for you.


               Become Your Own Banker

               In general, there are three kinds of people in the
               world: spenders, savers, and bankers. Spenders live
               check to check at the mercy of creditors. Spenders
               make high-ticket purchases, but they pledge their
               future earnings to make those purchases. Savers
               are  smarter.  They  set  aside  money  for  future
               purchases. But when they use their savings, they
               lose  their  compound  interest  forever.  Savers
               assume that their diligence guarantees a brighter
               future. Is that really so?


                                   Proverbs 22:7
                 The rich rule over the poor, and the borrower is slave to
                                      the lender.



               Bankers, on the other hand, never interrupt the
               miracle of compound interest. They make high-
               ticket  purchases  using  other  people’s  money.
               When  business  opportunities  arise,  they  fund
               them without cutting the future  short. And the
               good news is, you don’t need a job at a bank to be
               that kind of banker!]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   There are some purchases that require financing.
                   Houses,  cars  and  education  are  simply  too
                   expensive to purchase with cash. Do you have a
                   mortgage? Credit cards? If so, you’re already aware
                   of the problem. The majority of Americans pay 30
                   to 40 percent of their money to someone else’s
                   bank.

                   The  revolutionary idea  that  you  could  become
                   your own banker owes much to R. Nelson Nash,
                   the financial genius behind Infinite Banking. Instead
                   of giving your money to another bank to use, why
                   not  finance  major  purchases  with  your  own
                   money,  tax-free?  Nash  envisioned  building  a
                   personal      economic       system—the        CA$H
                   Residence—that would allow you to do just that.

                   Looking  for  a  loan?  While  money  is  still
                   compounding  inside  a  whole  life  policy,  the
                   insurance  company  will  let  you  collateralize
                   (borrow from) your policy and make you a loan.
                   They  do this  without any  financial  application.
                   When you are your own banker, the loan doesn’t
                   need an approval process. All you have to do is ask
                   for the loan, and it’s yours.

                   IRS Section 7702

                   Money inside a whole life insurance policy resides
                   in a completely different section of the income tax
                   code  than  IRAs  and  401k  plans.  Since  1985,


                                               61]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Section 7702 is where the tax freedom still exists
               and why billions are currently pouring into this
               area.


















































               Prior to 1985, the government kept a hands-off
               approach to  taxing life  insurance  policies.  The]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   reason for this was political—they didn’t want to
                   be seen as taxing widows and children. However,
                   the financial world began promoting investments
                   as “life insurance” to avoid paying taxes. Section
                   7702 was created to limit the tax-free benefits to
                   genuine life insurance policies.

                   Looking for tax diversification for your portfolio?
                   The CA$H Residence provides tax-free payments
                   to your beneficiaries, tax-free loans and gifts, and
                   cash  for  retirement  without  the  “harvest  tax”
                   that’s hidden in an IRA or 401k.

                   A Universal Benefit

                   So  far,  we’ve  taken  steps  to  understand  the
                   problem of  wealth-building and explain why so
                   many share the dream yet fail to attain it. We’ve
                   taken an objective look at traditional savings and
                   investment strategies in our search for the perfect
                   asset. And we’ve introduced you to an old strategy
                   that  is  too  often  overlooked  by  the  average
                   American. The CA$H Residence (PES) can be of
                   benefit to everyone.













                                               63]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                         Chapter Eight: What Do the
                                   Experts Know?


                   Suppose there was an institution that gathered the
                   greatest minds in the financial world. Economists,
                   accountants, financial analysts and attorneys, all
                   under one roof, all focused on the efficient use of
                   money. You’d want to know how they invested
                   the institution’s capital, wouldn’t you? You’d want
                   to know what the experts behind-the-scenes do to
                   maximize  growth  and  stability  while  reducing
                   taxes.


                   Banks and Cash Value Life Insurance
                   If there’s one institution that really  understands
                   the use  of  cash value  life  insurance, it’s  banks.
                   These financial institutions are involved in most
                   every aspect of our economy. Commercial banks
                   hold  billions  of  dollars  inside  cash  value  life
                   insurance policies. It’s one of their greatest secrets.
                   Why do they hold so much? Banks want to insure
                   their  future  profitability  and  existence.  Banks
                   enjoy the tax-free accumulation of the cash values.
                   What better  way  to  fund  employee  healthcare,




                                               65]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               pensions and other benefits than with a safe, time-
               tested strategy?

               Nearly every major bank makes their balance sheet
               public, according to FDIC rules and regulations.
               Take a look at just how much money some well-
               known banks hold in life insurance.



                 Banking Institution         Life Insurance Assets
                 Bank of America             $19,607,000,000
                 Wells Fargo Bank            $17,739,000,000
                 J.P.   Morgan  Chase  $10,327,000,000
                 Bank
                 U. S. Bank                  $5,451,892,000


               Banks place billions of dollars into life insurance.
               Is that important? You bet it is. Banks are in the
               money business. Placing their money in cash value
               life insurance is so common, financial experts have
               coined  jargon  to  describe  it,  including  “bank-
               owned life insurance” (BOLI). When corporations
               do  the  same,  it’s  called  “corporate-owned life
               insurance” (COLI).

               The  FDIC  allows  Life  Insurance Assets  to  be
               classified as Tier 1 capital—the safest capital. The
               amount of Tier 1 capital a bank has is considered
               to  be  a  good  measure  of  the  bank’s  financial
               strength  and  stability.  The  Office  of  The
               Comptroller  of  The  Currency  advocates  life
               insurance as an asset by making insurance part of]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   the banking laws. Up to 25 percent of commercial
                   banks’ Tier 1 operating capital can be invested in
                   life insurance.

                   Case Studies

                   Another way to approach the question, “What do
                   the experts know?” is to look for a track record of
                   how a particular option worked out for people in
                   the past. Let’s take a look back at some famous,
                   respected entrepreneurs and the companies they
                   founded, and see what the role of cash value life
                   insurance played in their success.

                   Nearly Wiped Out

                   The stock market crash of 1929 destroyed a lot of
                   companies.  One  chain  of  dry  goods  stores,
                   supplying important goods to  mining and farm
                   families,  was  particularly  hard  hit.  The  owner
                   suffered  from the  effects of  great physical and
                   mental strain. And his company was nearly wiped
                   out.

                                             What  saved  John  Cash
                                             Penney was his cash value
                                             life insurance policies. At a
                                             time of desperate need, he
                                             was able to borrow against
                                             those policies  to  pay  his
                                             employees  and  keep  his
                                             company  running.  After



                                               67]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               the  Great  Depression,  the  company—J.C.
               Penney—was able to rebound and become one of
               the  greatest  retail  companies  in  the  country.
               Today,  the  company  boasts  more  than  1,100
               stores worldwide, doing $18 billion a year in sales.

               An Icon is Born

               Ray was one of three partners who dreamed of
               creating  a  hamburger  empire.  The  other  two
               partners sold out after six years, though the chain
               still  bears their name. Meanwhile, Ray built the
               company  despite  almost  constant  cash-flow
               problems.






















               Anyone who knows about rapid business growth
               knows that sometimes, companies grow too fast.
               The bills can pile up quicker than the revenues,
               and suddenly, the success story is over. Ray was
               smart, though, and for  the first  eight years,  he]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   didn’t even take a salary. When times were tough,
                   he helped cover the salaries of key employees by
                   borrowing against his  cash  value  life  insurance
                   policies.

                   Ray Kroc believed in  the power of  advertising.
                   Though it’s not well known, Ray also used his cash
                   value life  insurance to help finance a marketing
                   campaign featuring a clown that would become a
                   fixture  in  American  pop  culture—Ronald
                   McDonald. The rest is history.

                   Today, McDonalds serves more than 50 million
                   people a day at more than 30,000 locations across
                   the globe.

                   A Clean Amusement Park

                   Back in  the day,  amusement parks  were  pretty
                   shady places. Carneys ran run-down attractions,
                   rip-off  “games  of  skill”  and  dangerous  rides.
                   Walter  had  a  vision  for  a  family-friendly
                   amusement park  that catered to the hopes and
                   dreams  of  children.  Needless to  say,  investors
                   didn’t  fall  over  themselves  to  give  Walter—a
                   cartoonist turned  entrepreneur—the money  he
                   needed.












                                               69]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer




                                            The vision was unique.
                                            Walter told a friend, “I
                                            want  it  to  look  like
                                            nothing  else  in  the
                                            world. And it should be
                                            surrounded by a train.”
                                            After  five  years  of
                                            planning,  the  project
                                            was  launched.  What
                                            many  people  don’t
                                            know  is,  Walt  Disney
                                            helped            finance
                                            Disneyland  and  other
               projects with cash value life insurance policies.

               Think of what an impact Disneyland has had on
               our culture! Our whole perception of amusement
               parks has changed, thanks to the vision of the man
               who gave  us  feature-length cartoons, television
               shows and, of course, a certain mouse…

               From Typhoid to Tutelage

               Leland and Jane  lost a  son to  typhoid fever,  a
               devastating  disease  that  plagued  mankind  for
               centuries (typhoid once wiped out a third of the
               population  in  ancient  Athens,  Greece).  To
               compensate for the loss of their son, the couple
               decided to dedicate their  lives  to helping other
               people’s children. They founded a University, and
               enrolled 555 students in just the first year.]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   Then, tragedy struck again. Leland died just two
                   years after the university’s founding, leaving Jane
                   with financial struggles and the prospect of a failed
                   enterprise.

                   But Jane would not give up on the dream. She was
                   able to survive six years of fragile finances with the
                   proceeds  from  her  husband’s  cash  value  life
                   insurance. The faculty  was paid and operations
                   continued uninterrupted.

                   Today,  Stanford  University,  Leland  and  Jane
                   Stanford’s  dream,  boasts  more  than  15,000
                   students, both graduate and undergraduate. The
                   university is one of the most respected schools in
                   the country.



























                                               71]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer




               What’s Cooking?

               Doris had been a  Tupperware salesperson, and
               was actually pretty successful at it. The business
               model seemed sound. But wouldn’t she be even
               more successful running a company of her own,
               using a similar model?

               Doris  believed that some of  the cooking tools
               available to women in the home were inferior to
               the  ones  available  to  chefs  in  restaurants. She
               imagined  success  selling  professional-quality
               cooking products in-home, using the “sales party”
               techniques she’d learned. Using her cash value life
               insurance policy,  Doris funded a  company that
               started in  her  basement and became a  national
               phenomenon.]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Today,  Pampered  Chef  is  a  billion-dollar
                   enterprise with more than 12 million customers.
                   Doris Christopher turned a dream and a vision
                   into a fortune.

                   But not without financial help.

                   America  is  experiencing  a  life  insurance
                   renaissance, fueled  by  individuals with financial
                   wealth who seek to protect their money from the
                   Government and look to diversify to mitigate the
                   risk  of  Wall  Street  volatility  and  uncertainty.
                   Armed with contracts that guarantee safety and
                   performance (something Wall Street cannot and
                   will not do), the wealthy put their money in cash
                   value insurance.
































                                               73]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                   Chapter Nine: The Private Reserve
                                        Account


                   The Private Reserve Account is a cash value life
                   insurance policy that pays a tax-free death benefit,
                   but also pays dividends that increase the policy’s
                   cash value. That cash value has unique advantages.
                   We’ve been calling this kind of account the CA$H
                   Residence. Next, we’re going to zero in  on the
                   benefits of this asset, which allows you to be your
                   own banker and guide your own financial destiny.

                   First, let’s take a moment to see how insurance
                   works.  Insurance  companies  begin  with  a
                   statistical model on a large population data base,
                   making certain to include people of all ages. An
                   actuarial—a person who computes risk based on
                   statistical  information—develops  the  model.
                   Next, a  rate  maker takes the  information and
                   determines what a company will have to charge in
                   order to meet death claim obligations. Once rates
                   are set, lawyers create legal, binding contracts that
                   are offered to the public through a sales force. The
                   insurance  company  creates  an  administrative
                   group to oversee the whole system.


                                               75]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer




               Take a moment to think about this. The insurance
               company doesn’t own the contract. The owner of
               the  contract  is  you.  The  insurance  company
               promises to do certain things as long as you meet
               acceptability standards and make your premium
               payments. Those premium payments are “put to
               work,” in order to produce the benefits promised.
               Insurance  companies  invest  in  conservative
               financial instruments (bonds, mortgages), and to a
               lesser extent, real estate or joint ventures.

               Because  you  own  the  contract  (policy),  you
               outrank all other stakeholders in the process. You
               have first option to use the money at an agreed
               upon interest rate.

               At the end of  the year,  the insurance company
               directors ask, “How did we do in comparison to
               the assumptions made by the actuaries and rate
               makers?” Based on that comparison, a dividend
               may be declared. That dividend is not taxable.

               Why not? Let’s look at an example. Suppose you
               buy a policy would require $1,000 a year to meet
               obligations. Several factors may alter  the actual
               cost of that policy. Administrative costs may go up
               or down. More or fewer death benefits may have
               to be paid. Earnings may vary from estimates as
               well.  Knowing  this,  the  insurance  company
               charges $1,100 a year. The extra “fudge factor”
               helps keep the system safe.]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   When the directors meet, they discover that the
                   policy  you  purchased only  cost  $800 a  year  to
                   maintain. Now,  they  have  a  decision  to  make
                   about the surplus. In this case, the directors place
                   $200  in  a  contingency  fund,  and  return  the
                   remaining $100 as a dividend.

                   So why is the dividend not taxable? Technically,
                   the  dividend  isn’t  a  gain—it’s  a  “return  of
                   premium.” Unlike stock shares, which may lose
                   value  if  the  stock falls,  the dividend can’t lose
                   value. You will use the dividend to purchase paid
                   up  insurance  (which  does  not  cost  a  sales
                   commission  or  fees),  thus  increasing  the  tax-
                   deferred accumulation of cash value.

                   Insurance policies are designed to become more
                   efficient over time. Over the life of the policy, the
                   cash value is guaranteed to reach the face amount
                   of  the  policy.  As  dividends  are  applied,  the
                   insurance company faces an ever-decreasing “net
                   amount of risk.” The news is filled with stories of
                   financial institutions (including Wall Street) that
                   leave widows and children penniless. When was
                   the  last  time  you  read  about  a  life  insurance
                   company  that  failed  to  meet  its  obligations?
                   Instances are statistically insignificant, for reasons
                   we’ve just explored.





                                               77]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Banking on Yourself

               Now that you understand the process, we can talk
               about  the  advantages  of  the  private  reserve
               account. The essential idea of the account is to
               recover the interest you  might normally pay to
               banking institutions through the use of dividend-
               paying life insurance, and then lending those funds
               to  others  so  that  the  policy  owner  makes the
               money that a banking institution does. Funds may
               be  lent  to  any  party  (including  your-self)  and
               earnings  grow  within  the  policy,  tax-deferred.
               Thus, you are both reducing your tax burden and
               capturing  monies  for  yourself  that  a  banking
               institution normally would normally receive.

               Anytime you can cut the payment of interest to
               others and direct that same market rate of interest
               to  an  entity  you  own  and  control,  subject  to
               minimal taxation, then you  will  have improved
               your wealth-generating potential significantly.

               It’s About Financing

               We’re  not talking  about investing here.  In  the
               introduction to this book, we discussed investing
               verses  saving.  Here,  we’re  talking  about
               financing—providing funding for  a  person or
               enterprise. Financing involves both the creation
               and maintenance of a pool of money and its use.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   What makes the Private Reserve Account special
                   is that when a financing system is combined with
                   an investment system, the combination will always
                   outperform an investment system. And when the
                   system combines a financing engine with reduced
                   tax liability,  allowing you  to maintain complete
                   control, the result is an ideal system.

                   Let’s see how the system works. Suppose you plan
                   to buy a car. You might finance it. When you’re
                   done paying off  the principle  and interest, the
                   bank has your interest money and you have an old
                   car. Or perhaps you’ll lease the car. The payments
                   will be less, but you won’t own the old car when
                   the lease ends—the bank will.  Can you  win by
                   paying cash? No interest, right? No interest for the
                   bank—or for you. Instead of building wealth, your
                   money is gone.

                   Now  imagine  financing  a  car  with  your  own
                   money,  borrowed  from  the  private  reserve
                   account, which is still accumulating interest, even
                   though the money is “in use.” By becoming your
                   own source of financing, you beat the banks at
                   their own game!



                      The avoidance of taxes is the only intellectual pursuit
                                 that still carries any reward.
                           John Maynard Keynes, Economist







                                               79]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               I think we can agree that we are all involved in
               elements of finance. If you pay interest to anyone
               else, or give up interest that could have been yours
               (opportunity costs), you are financing something.
               All the more reason to become your own banker!
               Between your occupation and your role as banker,
               which is more important? Consider the following:


                   •  Americans spend a large portion of their
                       annual income on interest expense.
                   •  In addition, the average American spends
                       about $0.30 of every dollar on taxes.


               Now, if you’re paying half of every dollar on
               taxes and interest, then your personal wealth
               would be greatly influenced by any strategy that
               captures interest while limiting tax liabilities,
               right? In fact, the impact would be greater than
               identifying good investments with high rates of
               return!

               But what about families? What about the CA$H
               Residence is of particular value to them? Read on!]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                    Chapter 10: Flexing Your Way to a

                                  Brighter Future

                   So far, so good, right? Believe it or  not, there’s
                   more good news ahead.

                   But first, let’s take a moment to explore how banks
                   make their money.

                   Suppose you  invest in a  Certificate of Deposit.
                   They pay you a small interest rate, and loan your
                   money to others…at a higher rate of interest. This
                   is  called  arbitrage—taking advantage of  differing
                   interest rates in an investment environment.

                   Now, suppose you invest in a $5,000 Certificate of
                   Deposit at two percent interest. At the end of the
                   year, the bank pays you $100. That’s the bank’s cost
                   of  sales.  Meanwhile,  they  loan  the  money  you
                   invested to your neighbor so he can buy a used car.
                   He pays five percent interest ($250).

                   The bank isn’t just  making three percent (your
                   neighbor’s five percent minus your two percent).




                                               81]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               The bank “invested” $100 and made $250—a 250
               percent return on investment. How’s that for a
               rate of return!

               You might wonder why banks don’t loan out their
               own money. Suppose a bank loaned you their own
               money. Continuing with your example, you’d pay
               the loan back and they’d earn six percent interest
               for their trouble. Small potatoes.

               But when a bank loans out your money, and pays
               you with your neighbor’s money, the rate of return
               is  much higher, and the risk  is  negligible. (The
               FDIC backs the loans of accredited banks.)

               Worse,  as  the  rate  of  interest  goes  down, the
               percentage  of  return  on  investment  goes  up.
               Suppose your CD pays one percent interest, and
               the car loan goes down to four percent interest.
               Same three percent markup, right? But their cost
               of sales is  now $50, and the neighbor’s interest
               payment is $200. That’s a 400 percent return on
               investment!

               What if you want your money back? You can’t—
               not  without  paying  a  penalty  and  losing  your
               interest on the CD.

               But wait, there’s more! Banks are only required to
               have a small percentage of their loan assets “on
               hand.” This is called the reserve requirement. If a bank
               is only required to hold ten percent of its money,]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   and the bank has $200 million in assets, they can
                   loan  out  $2  billion!  Your  little  Certificate  of
                   Deposit allows them to loan ten times that much
                   money to others at a higher rate of interest!

                   That’s how banks do it. One might even suggest
                   that the  perfect money solution  would involve
                   opening your own bank. Luckily, you don’t have
                   to invest in  a brass and marble edifice to use a
                   banking principle to amplify the benefits of the
                   missing piece.

                   The flex method uses leverage much as a bank does.
                   By adding money (via a credit line), investors can
                   maximize the size of the policy. Let’s see what kind
                   of effect that strategy has on policy returns.

                   First,  let’s  make  some  basic  assumptions  for
                   comparison purposes. Assume you invest $10,000



                                 $10,000 x .05 = $500



                   in  a  whole life  policy that yields a  five  percent
                   return. Not a bad return, these days. That means a
                   yield of $500 dollars.














                                               83]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Now,  suppose you  use  a  line  of  credit  to  put
               $50,000 of the bank’s money into your policies.
               The  same  five  percent  return  will  yield
               considerably more. Of course, you’ll have interest
               to pay on the loan. Let’s assume three-and-a-half
               percent on your loan. Since you’re getting a five
               percent return, you net a percent-and-a-half profit
               on your bank money. So, what’s your comparative
               yield?



                            $10,000 x .05 = $500
                           $50,000 x .015 = $750

                           Total return = $1,250


               The bank is satisfied because the interest on the
               credit line is paid. And because you leveraged bank
               money, your  return is  twelve-and-a-half percent
               on your actual $10,000 investment. That’s a world
               class return, but it’s not the whole story. Because of the
               flex  method, the  bank funding  provides  vastly
               superior death benefit coverage because the policy
               is larger…courtesy of the credit line.

               But suppose the bank’s interest rate changes, or
               the  policy’s  rate  of  return  drops below  what’s
               expected? What then? You simply adjust the policy
               and pay off the loan. After all, the money hasn’t
               gone anywhere.]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Later, when terms are more favorable, you begin
                   “flexing” again.

                   Does the flex method work? You are using the
                   bank-tested principle of leverage to invest in the
                   safest liquid asset on the planet. As for taxes, the
                   flex method deals in cash life insurance—the top
                   legal tax shelter in America today. All the benefits
                   of the missing piece—amplified!














































                                               85]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence

















                         Chapter Eleven: The CA$H
                            Residence and Families




                   I speak now from personal experience. For many
                   years now, in both my writing and consultation
                   of individuals, I used a particular phrase
                   frequently: My greatest calling is to be a dad.


                   In all my years, there has never been a greater
                   calling than the opportunity to be a father to my
                   children. That role has been the greatest joy of
                   my life. My wife and I are blessed with a safe
                   home. Cindy and I are committed to keeping our
                   home a sanctuary.


                   From a Biblical perspective, I have a mandate to
                   be the provider and the protector of our home.
                   The sanctuary we cherish isn’t free. We have to
                   work for it.




                                               87]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer




                                 1 Timothy 5:8
                 If anyone fails to provide for his relatives, and
                 especially for those of his own family, he has
                 disowned the faith and is worse than an unbeliever.




               I am fully aware that God is our source, the
               source of everything. He sees a sparrow when it
               flies and when it falls, and is certainly aware of
               my successes and failures. But from a Biblical

               perspective, the Word declares that I should be
               wise and a good steward, both of my time and my
               finances.


                                 Proverbs 13:22
                 A good man leaves an inheritance to his children’s
                 children. And the wealth of the sinner is stored up
                 for the righteous.



               In previous chapters, I’ve written about the
               opportunities that the CA$H Residence offers.
               For a father taking on family responsibilities,

               taking direction from scripture, the benefits are
               obvious. But are there other benefits that families
               ought to consider?

                   •  Between a mortgage, car loan, credit cards
                       and other debt, most Americans face]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                          decades of debt! What would it mean to
                          you to be completely out of debt in 10
                          years or less? That’s possible when you are
                          your own banker!

                       •  Do you have children who’d like to go to
                          college? The average cost of a single year
                          in college is nearly $23,000. Funds from a
                          policy grow tax-deferred. A policy taken
                          out on the life of a young child
                          accumulates cash value for a relatively
                          small premium. When it’s time for college,

                          the funds can be borrowed, keeping the
                          policy in force.
                       •  What if your child wants to supplement his
                          education with student loans? Cash value
                          life insurance is one of the few assets not

                          considered in federal college financial aid
                          calculations!
                       •  The CA$H Residence offers the possibility
                          of generational wealth. That is, you can
                          create legacy opportunities. Want to
                          provide your children and grandchildren
                          with a stake in the future? Perhaps you

                          want to provide a favored charity with a
                          legacy gift. It’s all possible with cash value
                          life insurance.








                                               89]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               The CA$H Residence offers value to nearly
               everyone. But for families, there’s more at stake.
               Are you beginning to see the possibilities? Read
               on!]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                       Chapter Twelve: Case Studies


                   Cody Woodrow is a cook for a popular restaurant
                   chain. Years over  a hot grill  gave him what he
                   needs in the way of expertise. Cody doesn’t mind
                   the long hours and sweat, because when he goes
                   home to his wife and daughter, his life is simple
                   and  blessed.  Cody  and  his  wife  are  amateur
                   photographers,  so  Cody’s  days  off  are  spent
                   looking for interesting photo subjects. Their eight
                   year-old daughter May loves to tag along.

                   Not long into her schooling, it becomes clear that
                   May is gifted. Her grades are consistently excellent,
                   and her achievement testing is off the charts. Cody
                   never went to college, but he’s determined that
                   May will have that opportunity.

                   He  fills  out a personal financial plan, and after
                   evaluating  options  that  fit  his  limited  income,
                   chooses cash value life insurance. A career in food
                   service leaves little room for financial error. Cody
                   opts for the absolute safety of a cash value policy.




                                               91]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Paying a  premium of $250 a  month, Cody will
               invest a total of $105,000 between the ages of 32
               and 67. His payout after retirement, spread over
               20  years,  will  be  $371,185!  More  important,
               though, is the opportunity to borrow against his
               cash value to permit May to go to the college of
               her choice. It’s too soon to know what field of
               study May will pursue, but it’s not too soon to plan
               her financial options!

               Trevor Kaine buys and “flips” houses for a living.
               His success depends on a number of varied skills
               and attributes, including a  background in  home
               inspections, an ability to research, and a seemingly
               endless well of patience (Trevor invests time in
               dozens of properties before buying one). When he
               finds a  property that he  knows he  can make a
               profit on, his background in construction becomes
               a huge personal asset. At age 37, he’s living the
               dream—success in business, a beautiful wife and
               three children.

               Because he’s made his money in real estate, Trevor
               has  a  healthy  respect  for  the  volatility  of  the
               market.  People  make  fortunes…and  they  lose
               them. Trevor wants to put the money he’s made
               someplace safe. As a responsible family man, he
               views their safety as his primary duty.

               Trevor and his wife Rose evaluate their finances
               and make the decision to take out a cash value
               policy with a big monthly premium. Trevor pays]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   $2,500 every month. If he retires at 67—30 years
                   from now—what will he have paid in? What will
                   his policy be worth?

                   All told, Trevor will have invested $900,000 in his
                   CA$H  Residence. At the end  of  30 years,  that
                   investment will  yield a  20-year annuity, with an
                   annual payout of $122,999—a total of $3,817,900
                   (tax free).

                   Of course, nothing ever goes exactly as planned.
                   When the three kids become teens, the driveway
                   becomes home to a lot of cars! Because Trevor is
                   his own banker, he arranges his own loans without
                   interrupting the continuous compounding of his
                   cash value. And when it comes time for a second
                   honeymoon, the trip to Europe is no problem. No
                   matter how many houses Trevor owns, his CA$H
                   Residence will  certainly  be  his  most important
                   residence!

                   Jazmine Owens is a single mother with a young
                   son.  Jerome  likes  to  play  sports  (especially
                   hockey),  watch  television  and  hang  with  his
                   friends. Mom works as a bookkeeper for the city
                   and supplements her income by teaching classes
                   online. On the weekends, mom watches her son
                   compete in school sports, so they have a busy life.

                   Then one night, Jazmine’s father asks about her
                   finances. He’s not being nosey—he’s just looking
                   ahead. Jazmine lives a comfortable life, so at first,


                                               93]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               she’s a little  taken back by her  dad’s questions.
               Driving home, she looks at her son and realizes
               that being comfortable just isn’t enough.

               After researching all of the possibilities, Jazmine
               decides to buy a cash value life  insurance policy.
               She plans to retire at 65. What will his choice mean
               in terms of dollars?

               Jazmine pays a $1,000 per month premium—using
               most of her second job’s income. They have to
               “tighten the belt” a little, but that’s not so bad.
               Over 25 years, her payments mean an investment
               of $300,000. (Of course, Jazmine has access to tax-
               free  loans  from  his  policy,  which  she  takes
               advantage of when she learns how much it costs
               to play hockey in high school!)

               When  Jazmine  retires,  her  death benefit has  a
               value  of  $712,952.  But  she’s  alive  and  well,
               enjoying  a  life  on  the  road  (her  son  is  a
               professional hockey coach!) That life is fueled, in
               part, by an annual payout of $59,720 over 25 years.]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence











                        Chapter Twelve: Starting the
                                    Conversation


                   This book has been about starting a conversation.
                   Chances are, you have been all too aware of the
                   problems inherent in wealth-building. Perhaps you
                   have  experience  with  some  of  the  traditional
                   solutions—those favored by the herd. Now, you
                   have a glimpse at an underappreciated asset that
                   has the potential to change your life—a vehicle
                   that can get you where you want to go.

                   It’s my opinion that the private reserve account
                   should be  the foundation for  every  American’s
                   personal finance strategy. To explain why, let me
                   use an analogy. In the days of westward expansion,
                   settlers often trusted the transfer of their personal
                   belongings  to  a  Conestoga  wagon—heavy,  a
                   heavy,  cloth-covered wagon designed to  travel
                   across all  kinds of  terrain.  Sturdy, iron-rimmed
                   wheels were central to the success of the wagon.
                   Each  wheel  featured  a  hub  and  a  number  of
                   spokes,  giving  support  to  as  much  as  12,000
                   pounds of  cargo! Along the way, spokes might




                                               95]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               break, but with a rock-solid hub, the wheel would
               continue to serve its purpose.

               Let me ask you: what is the hub of your financial
               wheel? If  your  life’s  journey  takes you through
               rough terrain, will your wheel continue to turn?

               In the introduction to this book, I differentiated
               between  savings  and  investments. The  private
               reserve account is the perfect savings strategy—
               the  sturdy,  dependable  hub  everyone  needs.
               Spokes—other investments from  stocks to real
               estate—may break along the way. But if the hub is
               solid, you can still move forward.

               So, what next?

               The journey to financial freedom is a path many
               look for and never find. I’m talking about freedom
               from  the shackles of  normalcy and mediocrity.
               Freedom  from  fear  and  uncertainty.  Freedom
               from the herd. Life is  about launching into the
               unknown and breaking free. This relentless pursuit
               is seen in the drive and actions of entrepreneurs
               and dreamers.

                          Be sure you’re right, then go ahead.

                          David Crockett, Frontiersman

               Think back to the early history of this country. Can
               you imagine the drive of the earliest pioneers, who]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   left everything behind and headed west without
                   maps,  without  guides?  They  packed  their
                   belongings, taking only what was necessary, and
                   forged  ahead in  search  of  a  dream.  And  their
                   friends and family? Most stayed behind.

                   SWSWSW is  an  acronym  I  frequently  use  in
                   training  and  workshops.  The  acronym  is  an
                   attitude and mindset which must be adopted. Some
                   Will,  Some  Won’t;  So  What?  Can  you  remove
                   yourself  from the expectations of  those around
                   you and set out on your own?


                     My interest is in the future because I am going to spend
                                    the rest of my life there.
                                    ~Charles Kettering

                   Let me challenge you to reach for your dreams.
                   Maximize  your  potential. Give  your  family  the
                   future they deserve. You’re at a fork in the road,
                   my  friend.  Will  you  follow  the  disappointed
                   crowd, or will you choose the road less traveled?

                   Consider the conversation started!















                                               97]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Appendix A: Life Insurance—an

                   Overview


                   The CA$H Residence (PES) approach to building
                   wealth  specifies  cash  value  life  insurance.  But
                   there’s more than one kind of life insurance. What
                   are the different types, and how do they differ?

                   Term Life Insurance pays a benefit to survivors in the
                   event of the death of an insured person. Policies
                   are in force for a set period of time. When the
                   policy  expires,  it’s  up  to  the  insured  party  to
                   purchase  another  policy.  Term  life  has  no
                   investment component.

                   Whole Life Insurance combines a death benefit with
                   an investment component. The cash value of the
                   policy  builds,  tax-deferred,  until  the  policy
                   matures.  You  can  borrow  money  against  that
                   accumulation, tax-free. Whole life is a cash value life
                   insurance, as described in this book.

                   Universal Life  Insurance combines a death benefit
                   with a money-market type investment for a higher
                   rate of return. Unlike cash value (whole life), the
                   higher rate of return cannot be guaranteed because
                   it’s tied to stocks and bonds that involve risk.










                                               99]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                   Appendix B: A Personal Plan for

                   Financial Success


                   In my work for the financial industry, I’ve found
                   that most people have already done some financial
                   planning. Maybe they have some investments and
                   some  insurance.  Perhaps  they  have  employee
                   benefits, or even a will. What they don’t have is an
                   understanding of how all of the pieces fit together.

                   A properly trained financial strategist will work on
                   what they call the offensive and defensive sides of
                   planning. The offensive side consists of savings,
                   wealth accumulation and entrepreneurial ventures.
                   The defensive side involves protecting against risk.
                   The  CA$H  Residence  attends  to  both  the
                   offensive and defensive.

                   Another aspect to consider involves the evolution
                   of thinking. Simply put, you don’t think the same
                   way when you’re 80 years old as when you’re 25.
                   We consistently hear older clients ask, “Why didn’t
                   someone explain this to me when I was younger?”

                   For these reasons, it’s imperative that you really
                   understand and comprehend the possibilities.

                   Now that you’ve read the book, you might have
                   questions. Can I do this? Where do I begin?





                                              101]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               Yes, you can build a  financial future.  Doing so
               involves beginning a journey of learning. There are
               possibilities and benefits to weigh. The subject of
               money is layered with nuance. I learn something
               new and exciting nearly every day. By reading this
               book, you’ve  taken the first  step on your  own
               journey.

               Knowing where you  want to go  is  part of  the
               formula. You need to set goals. But you also need
               to know where you are right now. Suppose you
               wanted to travel to Chicago. Would you go west?
               East? Your direction depends on your starting point.

               So, ask yourself: Where am I now? What have I
               done so far? Answering those questions involves
               gathering some information:


                   •  Family status—spouse? Do you have
                       children? If so, how old are they?
                   •  Current position—what is your current job
                       and income?
                   •  Goals—what are your retirement
                       aspirations?
                   •  Savings and Taxable Investments—what
                       stocks, mutual funds and savings accounts
                       do you have?
                   •  Qualified retirement accounts—do you
                       currently have a 401K or IRA?

                   •  Defined benefit plans—are you vested in
                       an employer-defined retirement plan?]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                       •  Real Estate—do you own property?
                       •  Risk protection—health insurance? Auto?
                          Property? Long-term disability? Term life
                          insurance?

                       •  Expenses—what mortgages, loans, and
                          credit card debt are you carrying?
                       •  Future expenses or income—Are college
                          expenses in your future? Weddings?
                          Inheritances? Are you vested in any
                          company retirement plans?

                   Then, do your homework. Take an objective look at
                   your  options.  If  you  happen  to  want  more
                   information from me, you are welcome to call for
                   an appointment or e-mail me. I would be honored
                   to help you with your personalized plan.


                   Contact Information:


                   David A. Saucer
                   Mobile: 225-907-6000
                   https://www.safemoneydavidsaucer.com/

                   Set an appointment with David today:
                   https://calendly.com/davidsaucer














                                              103]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence




                   Appendix C: Suggested Reading


                   Now  that you’ve  begun  your  learning  journey,
                   here is some suggested reading to help you on your
                   way:

                       •  Becoming Your Own Banker (Nelson
                          Nash)
                       •  The Fall of Logic (Chase Chandler)
                                                              st
                       •  Financial Independence in the 21  Century
                          (Dwayne Burnell, MBA)

                       •  The Great Wall Street Retirement Scam
                          (Rick Bueter)
                       •  How Privatized Banking Really Works (L.
                          Carlos Lara and Robert P. Murphy, Ph.D.)
                       •  The Millionaire Next Door (Thomas
                          Stanley and William Danko)
                       •  The Wealthy Physician (Chase Chandler)
                       •  Opportunity Cost in Finance and
                          Accounting (H. G. Heymann and Robert
                          Bloom)

                       •  The Richest Man in Babylon (George S.
                          Clayson)

                       •  The Trillion Dollar Meltdown (Charles R.
                          Morris)
                       •  The Wealthy Family (Chase Chandler)
                       •  Understanding the Modern Culture Wars
                          (Paul A. Cleveland, Ph.D.)




                                              105]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                                       Citations


                   “Brainy Quote” n.d. Web 22 Sep 2014.
                   http://www.brainyquote.com/

                   “Doubling Pennies” n.d. Web 22 Sep 2014.
                   http://mathforum.org/dr.math/faq/faq.doublin
                   g.pennies.html

                   "FDIC: Institution Directory." FDIC: Institution
                   Directory. N.p., n.d. Web. 31 Dec. 2013

                   "Five Reasons 8 Out of 10 Businesses Fail."
                   Forbes. Forbes Magazine, n.d. Web. 27 July 2015.

                   "RMS Manual of Examination Policies." Federal
                   Deposit Insurance Corporation, n.d. Web. 2
                       Jan. 2014.
                   <http://www.fdic.gov/regulations/safety/manu
                   al/section3-7.pdf>.

                   “The Greatest Retirement Crisis in American
                   History.” Forbes. Forbes Magazine. n.d. Web 26
                   June 2015.

                   “Things People Said: Bad Predictions” n.d. Web
                   22 Sep 2014.
                   http://www.rinkworks.com/said/predictions.sht
                   ml





                                              107]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer



               "Welcome to InflationData.Com." Welcome to
               InflationData.com. N.p., n.d. Web. 05 Aug. 2015.]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



                                 About the Author


                   David is a lifelong resident of Louisiana. In the
                   second year of seminary, he saw a girl in the lunch
                   line and his life was changed—he’s been happily
                   married for more than 25 years.

                   David has two children. Kaleb is 23 and Chloé is
                   21. His children are his greatest joy, and he proudly
                   proclaims his greatest calling is to be a Dad.

                   As a licensed minister, he has joyfully served in
                   many capacities. Over two decades, he has been
                   involved in the financial services industry, helping
                   thousands of  families  and business  strategically
                   plan for the future.

                   David’s  passion  is  family  and  making  lasting
                   memories.
























                                              109]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[David A. Saucer]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[The CA$H Residence



































































                                              111]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="114"/></pages></Search>
